Guide to the Germany. Extraparliamentary movement, 1967-1984
Department of Special Collections
Germany. Extraparliamentary movement,
1967-1984
Special Collections M0613
50.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1992.
Scope and Content
Auerparliamentarische Bewegung (APO), Studentenbewegung, Antiautoritäre Bewegung, Linke und Alternative Gruppen nach 1967. (Extra-parliamentary opposition, student movement; anti-authoritarian movement; leftist and alternative groups post 1967).
This collection contains over 4,500 pieces, mostly journals, magazines, newspapers, pamphlets, texts, books and posters. It was put together systematically over a 10 year period and has been continually modified in order to provide detailed and representative documentation of the following subjects:
2. Juni 1967 (June 2, 1967). The murder of student Benno Ohnesorg at a anti-Shah demonstration in Berlin. This spectacular event triggered the anti-authoritarian protest movement, documented here in flyers, magazines, journals and newspapers.
Vietnamkrieg (Vietnam War). Pamphlets, texts, newspapers, magazines and journals document the protest against the Vietnam War. (1966-1975)
Hochschulpolitik (University Politics). University revolt, occupation of institutions, anti-University, referred to as the Kritische Universität (critical university). Some of the independent lectures, seminars and events that were organized, as well as the aims of the movement that were communicated to the public are documented here through pamphlets, texts, magazines and journals. (1967-1975)
Betriebsarbeit (Factory Work). Part of the protest movement attempted to create an alliance with the workers. Grassroots groups and factory work were organized, and factory newspapers, pamphlets for workers, as well as magazines and journals were established. (1968-1972)
Kinderladenbewegung (Child Daycare Movement). The first socialist daycare center was founded in 1968 in Berlin. Anti-authoritarian education was discussed and psychoanalysis, especially the writings of Wilhelm Reich, was rediscovered. Pamphlets, texts, pirate press editions of classics of Psychoanalysis document this movement. (1967-1972)
Springer-Kampagne (Springer Campaign). In protest against the rabble-rousing propaganda of the Springer press (BILD-Zeitung) in Berlin, several anti-public forums emerged, including independent newspapers and pamphlets. (1967-1972)
Notstandsgesetze (Emergency Laws). Criticism of the emergency laws legislated by the grand coalition of the SPD and CDU was an important component of the extra-parliamentary movement. This criticism was also leveled against the established parties. Pamphlets, texts, newspapers. (1967-1970)
Frauenbewegung (Women's Movement). Starting with the Aktionsrat zur Befreiung der Frau (The Action Committee for the Emancipation of Women) (1968), the beginnings of the women's emancipation are documented through magazines, journals, pamphlets and texts. (1968-1973)
Stadtguerilla (Urban Guerillas). Armed struggle, Red Army Faction (RAF), Movement of the 2. June, Revolutionäre Zellen, (revolutionary cells) Terrorism are documented through illegal pamphlets, texts written by the groups, police Wanted-for-Reward posters, pamphlets, texts on the trials, as well as events following the death in Stammheim in 1977 of first generation RAF activists [Deutscher Herbst (German Autumn)]. (1968-1980)
Rote und schwarze Hilfe (Red and Black Assistance). After part of the movement was made illegal, groups and collectives of lawyers --analogous to those of the Weimar Republic--were formed that supported convicted prisoners. (1968-1980)
Raubdrücke (Pirate Presses). The Raubdrücke were initially part of the student movement, which printed mainly writings of the Frankfurt School, Critical Theory and Psychoanalysis, that were then unavailable in book stores. The first Raubdrücke were highly imaginative products, self-defined as Anti-Bücher (Anti-Books). Aesthetics, Printing Processes, Format, etc.. Emergence of independent presses. Books, texts, programs. (1967-1975)
Sozialistischer Deutscher Studentenbund (SDS) (Socialist German Student Oranization). The SDS was the most radical and important driving force of the student movement. Internal papers, pamphlets, materials on congresses document the activity of this organization. (1966-1970)
Häuserkampf (Housing Revolt). Pamphlets, texts, newspapers, magazines and journals document the occupation of buildings in Berlin and Frankfurt between 1968 and 1970, and between 1978 and 1982.
Anarchismus und Rätekommunismus (Anarchism and Council Communism). Anarchistic and council-communist groups emerged which later regarded themselves as in opposition to the dogmatic party communist ideas that came to dominate the student movement. Magazines, journals, pamphlets, texts. (1968-1975)
K-Gruppen (C-Groups) Communist Party - oriented groups formed in accordance with world-political models, such as those found in the Soviet Union, China, Cuba, Vietnam and North Korea. Pamphlets, texts, newspapers and journals. (1968-1975)
Tunix-Kongress 1978 (Do-Nothing Congress 1978). Important international congress of the anti-authoritarian movement in Berlin. Pamphlets, texts, newspapers. (1978)
Edition Voltaire. This press was founded by Bernward Vesper [ Die Reise (The Trip)]. It published a series of Voltaire-Schriften (writings) and Voltaire Handbücher (paperbacks) in which various revolutionary and militant movements, such as the Black Pathers, Zengakuren and the RAF, were given a forum. It also published works by writers, such as Jean-Paul Sartre, Heinrich Böll, H.M. Enzensberger, Günter Grass and Peter Weiss. Complete collection of the press' entire production, with ca. 50 titles.
Peter-Paul Zahl Verlag. The writer and typesetter P. P. Zahl was initially the printer of the anti-authoritarian movement in Berlin. He was the printer for the SDS, grassroots groups, and later even the RAF. He also founded his own press and published books, posters, magazines, Zwergschul-Ergänzungshefte, the series PP Quadrat, the literary [UNK] magazine Spartakus, the newspaper FIZZ, among other things. Later he founded the Rote Ruhr-Armee, a self-defined anarchistic faction of the RAF. The collection includes all the works of the press, including ca. 50 titles and texts expressing solidarity with the publisher during his longterm imprisonment.
Kommune 1. The K I was the [UNK] most well-known political group in Berlin. It began by developing new forms of protests, including Happenings and political/cultural events. Its members distributed and produced their own texts and pamphlets. In 1968 it was thrown out of the SDS. It later participated in the RAF and the 2. June Movement. Complete collection of its pamphlets and texts.
II
To these nineteen areas, a collection of all the important magazines, journals and newspapers of the anti-authoritarian movment have been added, providing a complete portrait of the movement:
882 (Agit 883). The most famous newspaper, in which all factions and perspectives between 1968 and 1972 were given a forum. 89 issues.
RPK (Rote Presse Korrespondenz). Between 1969 and 1973, approximately 160 issues appeared. Important supplement to 883. All events, demonstrations, struggles as well as intellectual and theoretical work were documented here.
Hundert Blumen. 1972-1973. Successor to 883. (complete)
Bambule. 1972-1974. Successor to 883.
Der lange Marsch. [UNK] Newspaper for a new Left. 1972-1978. Complete series. [UNK]
Info-Bug. (Info Berliner undogmatischer Gruppen). 1974-1978. Complete series of all 230 issues, including illegally printed ones that appeared after the magazine was banned. All groups and orientations of the movement were given a forum here to express themselves.
Radikal. 1976-1984. Originally conceived as a continuation of 883. Approximately 120 issues, some of which were printed illegally.
Konkret. This complete collection, which documents the continuity and multifacetness of the movement, is supplemented by an array of Konkret magazines published between 1958-1966 (122 issues). This important magazine marks the beginnings of the radical movement in the Federal Republic of Germany.
alternative. This journal was first published in August, 1958, as a successor to Lyrische Blatter, the last three issues of which are included in this collection. Alternative was originally called a publication for lyric and prose, but evolved to include mostly essays on anti-authoritarian themes. The collection includes all 146 issues from August, 1958 to December, 1982, with some issues bound and published together. Also included are yearly summary pamphlets from 1964-1981 and four dokumente additions published from October, 1964 to June, 1968.
Note
The title of the collection is the English approximation of Ausserparliamentarische Opposition (APO), an inclusive name for many leftist and student groups whose particular interests and objectives were united in their anti-authoritarian objectives.
Access Terms
Ohnesorg, Benno.; Kommune 1.; Kommunistische Gruppe Bochum/Essen.; Kommunistische Partei Deutschlands.; Peter-Paul Zahl Verlag.; Rote und Schwarze Hilfe.; Socialist German Student Organization (SDS); Springer Press.; Tunix-Kongress 1978.; Feminism--Germany.; Student movements.; Germany--Social conditions--20th century.; APO (Ausserparliamentarische Opposition) Sammlung.; Alternative; Blatter fur Lyrik und Prosa.; Bambule.; 882 (Agit 883); RPK (Rote Presse Korrespondenz); Hundert Blumen.; Der lange Marsch.; Info-Bug.; Konkret.; Radikal.
Container List
- Underground
  - Zut International, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Witte Krant (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pang, 1973, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Rosa Revue: Unterhaltungsmagazin für Revolutionäre, 1977;Zentralorgan des Aktionkomittees Rosa Luxembourg (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Love, 1970? (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Germania, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Palazzo (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Acid Facts (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Catch-Up, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Plenum: Zeitung des Aktionbündnisses für freie politische Betätigung, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Texte zur anti-Nato Woche (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Scheisse: Underground Zeitung, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Rote Press Korrespondenz, 1969-1972
    - nos. 1-21 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - nos. 22-41 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - nos. 23-60 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - nos. 61-80 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - nos. 82-101 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - nos. 102-122 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Berliner Undogmatischer Gruppen Info
    - nos. 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - nos. 11-20 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - nos. 21-30 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - nos. 31-40 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - nos. 41-50 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - nos. 51-60 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - nos. 61-70 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - nos. 71-80 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - -----, Nov 11, 1975-June 13, 1977
    - nos. 81-90 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - nos. 91-100 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - nos. 101-110 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - nos. 111-120 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - nos. 121-130 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - nos. 131-140 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - nos. 141-150 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - nos. 151-160 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - -----, June 20, 1977-?
    - nos. 161-170 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - nos. 171-179; 1001-1003 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - nos. 181-190 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - nos. 191-1005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - nos. 1009-1018 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - nos. 1019-1027 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - nos. 1028-1033 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Der Lange Marsch: Zeitung für eine Linke Berlin, 1972?-1975,nos. 1-17, os = oversize; stored in different location (Box 6 os)
  - -----, 1975-1979?,nos. 18-27, 29-44 (Box 7 os)
  - Graswurzel Revolution, (Hamburg) 1973-1979,nos. 4-39 (Box 8)
  - Fizz, (Berlin) 1971,nos. 1-10 (Box 9 os, Folder 1)
  - Charlie Kaputt, (Berlin). nos. 1,3 (Box 9 os, Folder 2)
  - Radikalinski, (Berlin) 1969,nos. 3-5 (Box 9 os, Folder 3)
  - B.Z. (Berliner Zeitung), 1968,nos. 1-29 (Box 9 os, Folder 4)
  - Linkeck, (Berlin) 1968?,nos. 2-4, 6-7. (Box 9 os, Folder 5)
  - Bambule, (Berlin/Hannover) 1972-1973. (Box 10 os, Folder 1)
  - Hundert Blumen, 1972-1973 (Folder 1, Folder 2)
  - Agit 883, 1969-1970;Verlagsunterlagen (Box 11 os)
  - -----, [UNK] 1970-1972?,nos. 51-89 (Box 12 os)
  - Wir Wollen Alles, 1973-1975,nos. 1-25, 27 (Box 13 os, Folder 1)
  - Voll Drauf, Spandauer Jugendzeitung, 1973-1974,nos. 1-7 (Box 13 os, Folder 2)
  - Elda: Grosse Freiheit Presse Hamburg, 1973?,nos. 1-3 (Box 13 os, Folder 3)
  - FiDi Bus, (Berlin) 1972,nos. 2-3 (Box 13 os, Folder 4)
  - Kreuzberg Gehört Uns, 1972 (Box 13 os, Folder 5)
  - O.R.A., 1973 (Box 13 os, Folder 6)
  - Berliner Anzeiger, 1972 (Box 13 os, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Magazines (Box 13 os, Folder 8)
  - Plakat, (Stuttgart) 1968-1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - V.Z. ( Vietnam Zeitung), (Berlin) 1973 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - L.Z. (Zeitung für Lehrlinge und Jungarbeiter), 1971 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - ELDA (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Thesenpapiere (position papers) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - S.Z. INFO: Sozialistische Zentrum Stuttgart, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Kompost: Infoblatt von Grünen Zweig, 1974-1977,nos. 10-25 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Green magazines, incl. Grüner Zeit, Humus (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - -----, incl. Grüner Zweig; cards (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - magazines, incl. T4, Pang (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - papers, documents, catalogues (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Resonanz, Schwulachtel (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - documents (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - magazines (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - flyers, magazines (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - magazines, incl. Schwarzer Alltag, Song, Schwulachtel (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - -----, [UNK] incl. Sadid, Giessener Anzünder, AA Nachrichten (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - -----, [UNK] incl. Der schwarze Kanal. Also Beatles Songbook (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - -----, [UNK] incl. Traumstadt, Pflasterstrand, Underground (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - magazines: Pinx, 1967;misc., 1970s/1980s (Box 18)
  - Ulcus Molle Info, 1972?-1978
  - Ulcus Molle Info, 1979-1984 (Box 19)
- Rätekommunismus (Council Communism)
  - Seminar Info 1-5 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Flugblätter (pamphlets) (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Thesenpapiere (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Thesenpapiere (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Anarchismus (Anarchism)
  - Broschüre, Kataloge, Zeitschriften (texts, catalogues, journals) (Box 21)
  - Texts by authors including, Paul Goodman, Michael Bakunin, Peter Kropotkin, Erich Mühsam, Ernst Toller (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Broschüre (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Broschüre (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Interne Broschüre (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Befreiung, (Cologne) 1972-1976 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Kramer Verlag: Zeitschriften (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Anarchist Journals/Magazines (Box 24)
  - Anarchist Magazines, including Mad/Revolte, (Hamburg) 1971-1981;Die Aktion: Zeitschrift für Politik, Literatur, Kunst, (Hamburg), 1981-1984 (Box 25)
  - Bulletin: Das Organ der Anarchistischen Badischen Föderation, 1975 1978 (Box 26 os, Folder 1)
  - Der schwarze Gockler, 1978-1980 (Box 26 os, Folder 2)
  - SDS (Sozialistischer Deutscher Studentenbund)
    - SDS, nos. 0-20,22 (Box 27)
    - materials, incl. pamphlets, position papers
    - Neue Kritik: Zeitschrift Sozialistischer Studenten, (Frankfurt) 1965-1970
    - SDS materials, incl. position papers, newspapers articles, notes (Box 28)
    - SDS Info, (Frankfurt) 1969-1970,nos. 5, 7/8-15, 17-18, 20-21, 24-28 (Box 29)
    - Sozialistische Correspondenz, (Frankfurt) 1970 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - SDS - Korrespondenz, 1966-1968 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Flugblätter (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Flugblätter (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Notstandgesetze, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - -----, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Flugblätter (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Oberbaum Verlag (Berlin) (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Rudi Dutschke Materials (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - ----- (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Rote Hilfe: Nachrichten und Mitteilungen, 1971-1973 (Box 33 os)
    - Rote Hilfe (Box 34)
      - Flugblätter (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Rote Hilfe (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Rote Hilfe (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Kommune I
    - Flugblätter (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - misc. materials (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Tunix-Kongress, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - 2. Juni 1967materials (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Log; Berlin Manuskripte (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - P.P. Zahl Verlag (Peter-Paul Zahl Press)
    - P.P. Quadrat, nos. 1-5; Zwergschülergänzungshefte, nos. 1-22. Authors incl. Mao Tse-Tung, Günther Wallraff, Michael Bakunin, Friedrich Engels, Agitprop (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - materials; Paul Steegemann Verlag (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Springer Kampagne materials, incl. Psychoanalyse der Bild-Zeitung, defense by Springer, flyers (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Spartacus: Zeitschrift für lesbare Literatur, (Berlin) 1967-1970,nos. 1-4 Sonderheft 1 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Vietnamkrieg (Vietnam War)
    - Forward; Up Against the Wall, 1970-1973;Vietnam Exhibit (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - materials, incl. position papers, newspaper/magazine articles (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - --------, [UNK] incl. Heinz Abosch's Der Endlose Krieg: Bericht über Vietnam, (Frankfurt) 1966 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Stadtguerilla (Urban Guerillas)
    - RAF (Rote Armee Faktion) materials: documents, press releases, posters, flyers, texts, incl. Ulrike Meinhoff's Dokumente einer Rebellion (Box 38)
    - RAF materials: documents, texts, pamphlets, newpapers articles, posters (Box 39)
    - Hamburger Info, magazines, flyers for demonstrations (Box 40)
    - Revolutionäre Zellen/Revolutionärer Zorn: Zeitung der revolutionären Zellen, 1975-1978;flyers, texts (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Dokumentation: zu den Ereignissen und Entscheidungen im Zusammenhang mit der Entführung von Hans Martin Schleyer und der Lufthansa Maschine...; Bericht über den Polizeieinsatz in Krefeld am 25.6.1983 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Broschüre; Handbuch der Stadtguerillen (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - misc. materials (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Broschüre, authors incl. Ulrike Meinhof, Horst Mahler (Box 42)
    - newspaper/magazine clippings (Box 43)
    - 2. Juni. 1967 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - RC (Republikanischer Club) - Bulletin, (Berlin), ed. Solverig Ehler 1968-1969 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Internationalism, authors/subjects incl. Eldridge Cleaver, Harry Magdoff, Coup in Portugal; Latin American Politics (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Internationalism, subjects incl. Palestine, Iran, Turkey (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Häuserkampf (Housing Struggle)
    - newspaper/magazine clippings, flyers, press releases (Box 45)
    - Instand - Besetzer Post, (Kreuzberg) 1981,nos. 1-12 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - --------, nos. 14-23 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - nos. 23-31 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Der Besetzer, (Berlin) 1982 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Kreuzberger Stadtteil-Zeitung, 1970-1973,nos. 1-3, 9-10 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Humanes Wohnen, (Hamburg) 1973-1974 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - K Gruppen (Communist Groups)
    - Broschüre, incl. Rote Garde, Der Funke, Konsequent, 1967-1973 (Box 47)
    - Theoretische Thesenpapiere, authors incl. Ernst Mandel (Box 48)
    - Bolschewik: Theoretisches Organ der KPD/ML, ed. Zentralbüro der kommunistischen Partei Deutschlands/Marxisten - Leninisten, (Bochum) 1970-1971;miscellaneous newspapers (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Roter Pfeil: Organ der marxistischen-leninistischen Gruppen an der Universität Tübingen, 1970;Rote Fahne; Proletarische Front (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Freies Landvolk: Zeitung der revolutionären Landvolk - Bewegung, 1979-1980;RGO - Revolutionäre Gewerkschaft Opposition, (Frankfurt) 1979-1980 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - layout pages (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - texts, position papers, flyers, newspaper clippings (Box 50)
    - Rote Fahne: Organ der Stadteilkomitees der KPD - Aufbau, 1970-1977;Kommunistische Arbeiterpresse: Betriebszeitung der KPD, (Berlin) (Box 51)
  - Edition Voltaire
    - Voltaire Flugschriften, ed. Bernward Vesper (Berlin) 1966-1971,nos. 1-33 (7, 9,30, 32 are missing) Authors incl. Peter Weiss, Jean-Paul Sartre, Heinrich Böll, Günther Anders, Hans Magnus Enzensberger, Black Power, Günter Grass, Rudi Dutschke, Stockley Carmichael, Horst Mahler, Thorwald Throll, Leon Trotsky (Box 52)
    - Edition Voltaire Series: Projekte und Modelle, (Frankfurt/Berlin) nos. 1,3,4. Incl., R. Buckminster Fuller, Die Aussichten der Menschheit 1965-1985;Fuller, Erziehungsindustrie; Ossjp K. Flechtheim, Futurologie - Möglichkeiten und Grenzen (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Voltaire Flugschriften (Frankfurt/Berlin: Verlag neue Kritik - Voltaire Verlag), 1966;Klau Mich, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Edition Verlag - Voltaire Handbuch. Authors incl. Malcom X, Michael Schneider, Mao Tse-Tung, Ronald Steckel, Frank Benseler, Arno Ploog, Karl-Heinz Roth, Eckard Kanzow, Brigitte Heinrich (Box 53)
  - Internationalismus/Frauenbewegung
    - Chile, magazine articles, documents, texts, 1972-1973 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Chile, papers (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Women, Frauenhandbuch; Brot und Rosen (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Raubdrücke (Pirate Editions)
    - Theoretical Materials, incl. lists, documents, papers (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Raubdrücke; authors incl. Wilhelm Reich, Max Horkheimer, Mao Tse-Tung; calenders and address books (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Raubdrücke, authors incl, Karl Marx, Leon Trotsky (Box 56)
    - Raubdrücke, authors incl. Georg Lukács, Otto Rühle, Erich Fromm, G. Dimitroff, Karl Korsch, Wilhelm Reich, Isaac Deutscher (Box 57)
    - Raubdrücke; authors incl. Joseph Stalin, Siegfried Krakauer, H.M. Enzensberger, Otto Rühle, Theodor Adorno, Jürgen Habermas, Rosa Luxembourg, Michael Bakunin (Box 58)
    - Raubdrücke: authors incl. Herbert Marcuse, Max Horkheimer, Wilhelm Reich, Henryk Grossman, Leon Trotsky (Box 59)
  - Jugendliche Roter-Punkt-Bewegung; Lehrlinge (Youth Movement; Apprentices)
    - Roter Punkt; Agitation im Freizeitbereich, (Berlin) 1970 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Roter Punkt, (Heidelberg) 1969-1970 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Neues Rotes Forum, 1970-1972;misc. magazines (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Schülerbewegung/Kinderladenbewegung (School Movement/Daycare Movement)
    - Schülerbewegung: documents; flyers (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - ----- (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Kinderladenbewegung: documents, flyers (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - ----- (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Sozialisation. Schüler Jugendbewegung: documents (Box 62)
  - Sexualität and Sozialisation
    - Sex Pol-Info, Wilhelm-Reich (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Sozialisation und Sexualität: Theoretische Schriften (theoretical writings) (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - ----- (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Hochschulpolitik (University Politics)
    - materials, papers, flyers (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - -----, [UNK] (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - ----- (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - ----- (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - ----- (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Kritische Universität texts, 1967-1968 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Studenten und Presse in Berlin: Eine Untersuchung der Berichterstattung in Zeitungen und Zeitschriften über die Unruhen in Berlin am 2. Juni 1967und deren Hintergrunde, (Berlin: Axel Springer Verlag) (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Kritische Universität: Dokumentation des Arbeiterkreises Medizin und Verbrechen zum Thema Zwangsterilisation im 3. Reich, (Heidelberg) 1968 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Germanisches Seminar: Versuch einer Sprachanalyse nationalsozialistischer Texte, 1969 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - FU Spiegel: Offizielle Studentenzeitschrift an der Freien Universität, 1967-1969,nos. 44-46, 48, 51-52, 56-58 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - -----, [UNK] nos. 60-67, 70 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - FU Spiegel - Anrisse: Zeitung der Studenten der Technischen Universität Berlin, 1967-1969 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Veritas Justitia Libertas: Festschrift zur 200-Jahrfeier der Columbia University New York, überreicht von der Freien Universität Berlin von der Deutschen Hochschule für Berlin, (Berlin) 1953 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Colloquium: Eine deutsche Studentenzeitschrift, (Berlin) 1957-1967 (Box 66, Folder 2)